High-Octane Action and Daring Dogfights!
Red Tails is a drama, action, adventure film directed by Anthony Hemingway.
The story of the Tuskegee Airmen, the first African-American pilots
to fly in a combat squadron during World War II.
Colonel William Mortamus, played by Bryan Cranston.
Joe 'Lightning' Little, played by David Oyelowo.
Major Emanuelle Stance, played by Cuba Gooding Jr..
Sofia, played by Daniela Ruah.
Col. A.J. Bullard, played by Terrence Howard.
Antwan 'Coffee' Coleman, played by Andre Royo.
Red Tails is a 2012 American war film directed by Anthony Hemingway in his feature
directorial debut, and starring Terrence Howard and Cuba Gooding Jr.
The film is about the Tuskegee Airmen, a group of African-American United
States Army Air Forces (USAAF) servicemen during World War II.
The characters in the film are fictional, although based on real individuals.
The film was produced by Lucasfilm Ltd.
and released by 20th Century Fox, and would be the last film Lucasfilm released
before being purchased by The Walt Disney Company nine months later.
This was Cuba Gooding Jr.'s first theatrically released film in five
years since his starring role in 2007's Daddy Day Camp.
John Ridley wrote the screenplay.
Additional material was shot the following year with executive producer George
Lucas as director and Aaron McGruder as writer of the reshoots.
It was filmed in March and July 2009.
Red Tails was a personal project for Lucas, one that
he had originally conceived in 1988.
It is the first Lucasfilm production since the 1994 film Radioland Murders that
is not associated with the Indiana Jones or Star Wars franchises.
Terrence Howard had previously portrayed a Tuskegee pilot
in Hart's War (2002), and Cuba Gooding Jr.
had previously starred in The Tuskegee Airmen (1995), an HBO
made-for-television film about the same group of pilots.
The film explores themes of world war ii, fighter pilot, u.s.
air force, based on true story, fighter airplane.
The tone is emotional.